

JONATHAN CASTILLO

Software Developer



▶ ABOUT ME

B.Eng. in Computational Robotics with 1 year of experience developing web apps mostly with JavaScript (React, NodeJS, and Express). I am passionate and competitive, always eager to learn new things from challenges, self-learning, or being part of a team.



9911074078



jonathancastillovelazquez@gmail.com

Work Reference

Brianda Lara - Program Coordinator

- Cel. 9999691089
- brianda.lara@itksquare.edu.mx



SKILLS

Frontend

- React
- HTML
- **CSS**
- JavaScript / **Typescript**
- **Bootstrap**
- MUI

Backend

- Node is
- **Typescript**
- **Express**
- PostgreSQL
- Sequelize

Techniques

Web Development

- Agile Methodologies
- Responsive Web · Problem-solving Design
- GIT / GITFLOW
- Debugging
- Testing -Jest

Soft skills

- Work under pressure
- Detail-oriented
- Critical thinking
- Good Team
- Player Time
 - Management

Languages

- · Spanish (Native)
- · English (High level)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022 - 2023 | INSTITUTO TECNOLOGICO KSQUARE

JavaScript Associate Software Engineer - WebDeb

Rappi Clone

- •Work with Agile methodologies, GIT and Microservices-based architecture to develop the role-based "Point of Sales" app.
- •Use React and MUI for building a responsive SPA with reusable and scalable components that consumed our own API.
- •Use Node js and Express js for building a restful API, and socket.io to manage the full-duplex connection between clients and the server.
- •Use PostgreSQL as database and sequelize as ORM to store and manage the whole information.
- •Create authentication and authorization middlewares using Firebase Auth through tokens.
- •Create routing using react-router-dom and authentication using the context hook and tokens.
- •Implement WebSocket for User-POS immediate interaction (new orders). •Implement clean architecture and best practices for clean, reusable and scalable coding.

Health Management System

- •A role-based app developed working under Agile methodologies and
- •Use React and MUI for building a responsive SPA with reusable and scalable components that consumed my own API.
- •Use Node is and Express is for building a restful API.
- •Use PostgreSQL as database and sequelize as ORM to store and manage the whole information.
- •Create authentication and authorization middlewares using Firebase Auth through tokens.
- •Create routing using react-router-dom and authentication using the context hook and tokens.
- •Implement clean architecture and best practices for clean, reusable and scalable coding.

2020 - 2022 | UCHIYAMA MANUFACTURING DE YUCATÁN

Production Engineer

Head of the material processing area. I performed as a leader of engineers and operators to achieve the high-quality expectations of the company in that area.

- Just In Time - Jidoka -Lean Manufacturing - Kanban

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

2016 - 2020 | COMPUTATIONAL ROBOTICS ENGINEERING

Graduated - Universidad Politécnica de Yucatán

2022 | THE WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP 2022 BY COLT STEELE Finished - UDEMY

2023 | SALESFORCE JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER I CERTIFICATION

Certified - Salesforce

2022 - 2023 | JAVASCRIPT JUNIOR DEVELOPER

Certified - Instituto Tecnológico Ksquare